Preliminary Guide to the Otto Frey Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Otto Frey papers
1932-1964
MS 1330
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
Correspondence, speeches, personal and financial documents and papers related to Otto Frey's post as a member of the secretariat of the United Nations since 1945. Also included are a number of items of memorabilia, among them photographs, maps, clippings and printed matter.
Frey, Otto, 1907-1964
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Otto Frey, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Prague, on November 24, 1907, Otto Frey was the son of Maurice and Elsa Frey. He received an LL.D. Degree from Prague University in 1931, and spent the next few years at European universities as a researcher. During the 1930s and early 1940s, he worked for the Czechoslovak government, first for the minister of public works, but primarily for the foreign service. Immediately following World War II, Frey began working for the United Nations, specializing in disarmament. He died on January 25, 1972, while on vacation at Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, speeches, personal and financial documents and papers related to Otto Frey's post as a member of the secretariat of the United Nations since 1945. Also included are a number of items of memorabilia, among them photographs, maps, clippings and printed matter.
Czechs -- United States; Diplomats; Frey, Otto, 1907-1964; United Nations
- Inventory
  - Documents of immigration and appointment and related correspondence, 1939-1948, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, minutes of United Nations correspondence, 1936-1949 (Box 1)
  - Certificates of transport, declarations of death, related correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Invoices, bank correspondence, 1941-1951 (Box 1)
  - United Nations correspondence, 1947-1955 (Box 1)
  - Documents and certificates (marriages, birth, degree, school, etc.), 1920-1969 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  - Maps, undated (Box 1)
  - Sermon, speech, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1938, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Printed matter, 1932, 1938, 1948, 1952 (Box 1)